[
  {
    "question": "The scientific and systematic study of groups of humans",
    "answer": "Sociology"
  },
  {
    "question": "Being able to imagine reasons humans act",
    "answer": "Sociological Imagination"
  },
  {
    "question": "Founding father who applied scientific thinking to social life. He focused on social order and social change.",
    "answer": "Auguste Comte"
  },
  {
    "question": "Father of Social Darwinism and the first to apply Darwin’s survival of the fittest to society.",
    "answer": "Herbert Spencer"
  },
  {
    "question": "The physical aspects of culture",
    "answer": "Material Culture"
  },
  {
    "question": "The abstract aspects of culture",
    "answer": "Nonmaterial Culture"
  },
  {
    "question": "Rules best described as manners",
    "answer": "Folkways"
  },
  {
    "question": "An important type of rule",
    "answer": "More"
  },
  {
    "question": "Things all cultures have",
    "answer": "Cultural Universals"
  },
  {
    "question": "Things specific to a culture",
    "answer": "Cultural Relativism"
  },
  {
    "question": "The enforcement of norms through internal or external means",
    "answer": "Social Control"
  },
  {
    "question": "Indoctrinated to obey a norm means to",
    "answer": "Internalize a Norm"
  },
  {
    "question": "The act of breaking a norm in society",
    "answer": "Deviance"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who you are",
    "answer": "Status"
  },
  {
    "question": "Your most defining status",
    "answer": "Master Status"
  },
  {
    "question": "Inherited aspects that define you",
    "answer": "Ascribed Status"
  }, 
  {
    "question": "Achieved aspects that define you",
    "answer": "Achieved Status"
  },
  {
    "question": "Occurs when two roles have opposing values",
    "answer": "Role Conflict"
  },
  {
    "question": "Occurs when there is a scarcity of resources, time, or services that two separate roles require",
    "answer": "Role Strain"
  },
  {
    "question": "The tendency for people to act foolish in a group",
    "answer": "Risky Shift"
  },
  {
    "question": "Totalitarian groups restricting their member's rights",
    "answer": "Cults"
  },
  {
    "question": "The claim that GENETICS influences the development of humans is commonly called. . .",
    "answer": "Nature"
  },
  {
    "question": "The claim that ENVIRONMENT influences the development of humans is commonly called. . .",
    "answer": "Nurture"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 12-year-old who didn’t learn to verbally communicate because she was locked in a room her whole life. People wanted to test the critical period hypothesis by seeing if she could learn to speak at an advanced age",
    "answer": "Genie the Wild Child"
  },
  {
    "question": "The four agents of socialization are:",
    "answer": "Family, peers, school, mass media"
  }
]